(Music)
(موسيقى)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thank you.
شكراً لكم.
Hi, everybody.
اهلا جميعاً.
Ban-gap-seum-ni-da.
بان-قاب-سيم-ني-دا.
I'd like to share with you a little bit of me
اود ان اشارككم القليل عني
playing my life.
عزف حياتي.
I might look successful and happy
ربما ابدو ناجحه وسعيده.
being in front of you today,
ان اكون امامكم اليوم،
but I once suffered from severe depression
لكني يوماً عانيت من اكتئاب شديد.
and was in total despair.
وكنت في يأس شديد.
The violin, which meant everything to me,
الكمان، الذي يعني كل شي بالنسبه لي،
became a grave burden on me.
اصبح حملاً ثقيلاً علي.
Although many people tried to comfort and encourage me,
رغم ان كثير من الناس حاولوا مواساتي وتشجيعي،
their words sounded like meaningless noise.
كلماتهم بدت لي كأنها ضجيج بلا معنى.
When I was just about to give everything up
عندما كنت على وشك اسّلم كل شيء
after years of suffering,
بعد سنوات من المعاناة
I started to rediscover the true power of music.
بدأت في اعادة اكتشاف القوة الحقيقية للموسيقى
(Music)
(موسيقى)
In the midst of hardship,
في وسط الضائقة،
it was the music that gave me -- that restored my soul.
كانت الموسيقى من اعطتني واعادتي لي روحي.
The comfort the music gave me
المواساة التي اعطتني اياه الموسيقى
was just indescribable,
كانت فائقة الوصف،
and it was a real eye-opening experience for me too,
وكانت تجربة تنويريه حقيقه بالنسبه لي ايضاً،
and it totally changed my perspective on life
وغيرت نظرتي للحياه بشكل جذري
and set me free from the pressure
واعتقتني من ضغوط
of becoming a successful violinist.
ان اصبح عازفة كمان ناجحه.
Do you feel like you are all alone?
هل تشعر بالوحده ؟
I hope that this piece will touch and heal your heart,
اتمنى ان تلمس هذه المقطوعة قلبك وتشفيه،
as it did for me.
كما فعلت لي.
(Music)
(موسيقى)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thank you.
شكراً لكم
Now, I use my music to reach people's hearts
الان، انا استخدم موسيقاي لأصل الى قلوب الناس
and have found there are no boundaries.
واكتشفت انه لا توجد حدود
My audience is anyone who is here to listen,
جمهوري هو اي شخص هنا ليسمع،
even those who are not familiar with classical music.
حتى الاشخاص الغير معتاديين على الموسيقى الكلاسيكية.
I not only play at the prestigious classical concert halls
انا لا اعزف فقط في صالات الحفلات الكلاسيكيه المرموقه
like Carnegie Hall and Kennedy Center,
مثل قاعة كارنيجي ومركز كينيدي،
but also hospitals, churches, prisons,
لكن ايضا في المستشفيات، الكنائس، السجون،
and restricted facilities for leprosy patients,
ومرافق المقيدة للمرضى الجذام،
just to mention a few.
فقط لأذكر البعض
Now, with my last piece, I'd like to show you
الان، مع اخر مقطوعة، اود ان ازيكم
that classical music can be so much fun, exciting,
ان الموسيقى الكلاسيكيه من الممكن ان تصبح مرحة اكثر، ومثيره،
and that it can rock you.
وان يمكنها ان تهزك.
Let me introduce you to my brand new project,
اسمحولي ان اعرفكم بمشروعي الجديد،
"Baroque in Rock,"
"الباروك في روك"
which became a golden disc most recently.
والذي حصل على جائزه القرص الذهبي موخراً
It's such an honor for me.
انه لشرف عظيم لي.
I think, while I'm enjoying my life as a happy musician,
اعتقد، انه خلال استمتاعي بحياتي كعازفة سعيده،
I'm earning a lot more recognition than I've ever imagined.
اني اكسب تقدير اكثر بكثير مما حلمت به يوماً.
But it's now your turn.
لكنه الان دورك.
Changing your perspectives
غير منظورك للحياه
will not only transform you but also the whole world.
فهذا لن يغيرك فقط لكنه ايضا سيغير عالمك
Just play your life with all you have,
اعزف حياتك بكل ما تملك،
and share it with the world.
وشاركه مع العالم.
I really look forward to witnessing
اني اتتطلع بشده على ان اشهد
a transforming world by you, TEDsters.
على عالماً متغير بفضلكم، متحدوثو تيد
Play your life, and stay tuned.
اعزف حياتك، وابقى على النغمة.
(Music)
(موسيقى)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)